for the Myham Special Utility Authority to order.
Mr. Robert Greyd, a ladies and a friend.
Thank you for this day.
I thank you for each person here.
I pray God that you may be decisions.
You will be at the decision fate that I will be pleasing to you.
I thank you God for the people in this community that have served in the armed forces
that have given their time in some of their lives.
I ask Father to bless and bless her family.
I pray God that decisions might provide or pleasing me to you.
I pray this whole year since I am working with you.
Amen.
I pray the decisions to the flag of the United States of America,
and to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation under God, into this world with liberty and justice and so on.
I am number four.
Public in, but nope.
I'm moving right along.
Number five, consent agenda of the staff is asking us to approve item six and seven.
So moved?
Aye.
Number eight.
Budget amendment 22-32.
MSU-A wastewater collection receding.
An expanding Oklahoma Water Resources Board loans proceeds.
Jennifer.
Is for wastewater collection receding and reimburseing reimbursement.
Expending reimbursement of OWRB.
He gives a little bit of background on what that means.
Yes.
What it would be is with this reimbursement loan where we have expanded.
This is where allowed up to a certain dollar amount on this loan.
When we expand those, then we go ahead and get re-versed for that.
And so that's what this amendment is.
This is the one that helped me accounting for that.
Reversed.
Check glad he asked that question.
I wanted to.
Sir.
Sir glad I said.
Study about it.
Yes, man.
If you come in here, you better.
Make a motion.
We approve.
Second.
East End.
So.
Sunberg.
Davis.
Aye.
Budget amendment 23-0-2.
MSU-A.
Using Carrier Response for Personnel.
And this is a personnel race increased by contract.
And it occurred after the FY22-23 budget.
approved, and that's why we're needed to do it.
Second.
So, please step, send her Davis.
Hi.
Thank you, Jennifer.
Thank you.
Number 10, Action Item.
Davis writes remain claim for Pinscology RDA
reelection scene.
So, in your packet, we have a claim for Davis
write remain, and it is related to the Pinscology
RDA, a relicancy in the claim is for $33,510.
Is there not more information on this,
though, in terms of paperwork?
Oh, yes.
I don't have it with me here, but I can talk about it
at our next meeting.
If you'd like, but yeah, there's great
significant detail broke down by minutes and hours
on each invoice.
And I would suspect that this particular bill
were pretty much wrap up.
A lot of this significant activity that occurred
throughout the last part of the end of the last fiscal year.
And so, we're probably going to have pretty significant
slowdown until probably late in the fall,
maybe September, before activity picks up,
again, are in our next technical conference.
My only reason for my question is, when you see these,
week after week, and there's just kind of blank,
there's no line out of definition, right?
It denies if we could have some line out of definition,
so that we kind of understand, like, this is $33,000.
That's all we see on here, right?
And so, I would suspect that the way that these are broken
out in the detail providing would be something we'd
have to do an executive session to provide a discuss,
because a lot of it does have strategic detail
outlined in each of the bills.
I get that, and I hate to be labor anybody or anything,
but also point to make sure that we understand
that the deaths of what we're treating at proving,
I mean, I hope I'm not the only one that tells that way.
No, I can, in fact, I can give you any other,
and we can kind of come up with some other additional detail
you can want to see, you know, if we want to try to come up
with something that might provide you enough detail
to give you an idea of the activity without going
into significant detail.
Yeah, and I think that's what I think that's what I'm asking you for
is I'm not really asking for everything, you know,
I said line out, but really just a little bit more
information analysis, readers digest version, sure, yes.
Absolutely, yeah, there's there's plenty of detail that I can go through and then provide us an office of activity
So with this item hold to the 18 sure
I mean, I'll make that call and we just be
That's our next meeting
Yeah, they're I assume they would be fine. I feel better about it. How about sure after you?
Yeah, I'm just a detail. Be cool. Yeah, we can do that perfect
So then what is our what is our action here?
The action or you can postpone this to the next
So we need a motion for post comment
Hi
Number eleven action item award bid c 22 dash 28 purchase of two automated side loader refuse collection arms to
Dixon equipment company for forty three thousand nine hundred thirty three dollars for a total cost of eighty seven thousand eight hundred and sixty six dollars
That's Kevin
All right, number twelve action item award bid c 22 dash 17 contractor for 13.2
Kilbo
Line
Stead of babbling through the rest of it. I'll just hand it to you
So this is the award that it's you you see electrical services. So this is for your placement
Electricals and wires for different locations, so we have
I don't want 25 when you cross over the extra river. You have the area right there. It's been a lot of time and floodwaters
At there on your left
So we're changing those poles out from what both still poles. Actually why I'm just broken
So we're changing those up to steel and then from there by the pool. We'll turn and replace them going at that alley
To the substations of that whole feeder will be replaced and then every year first we know the whole
Where are they going to?
So I to the Southwest so there are two people here that we have that we feed
to the Southwest so we don't have the equipment to work on my big
of holes from the old warm meal plan that's going up to the Southwest too.
Yes, I know.
But do you ever feed so that way we have any of turn on off to work on it?
Let me get you out of that if I mean it's more pleasant to you.
Poor percentage of our poles have those squirrel guards on them now.
Every new goal is put in a grant number.
You're making a dent.
You have to look to find one that doesn't have it.
Yes, let's go.
We're actually going to work on it.
And then we use one of the word for reliability and safety.
Second.
Double.
Five.
Number 13.
Action item.
Resolution approving community financial support and feed waivers to K.O.
Water Wash related to the development of one thousand one north main.
But recent entire climb.
So, in front of you, you have got a resolution MSUA 22203.
That is for the MSUA.
And this is specifically the resolution details.
The information that we discussed at executive session.
And should outline the direction that we were given by council during that meeting.
Thank you, motion.
Second.
Question and possible action on solid waste trash disposal service and possible award
of bid 22-29.
A six month solid waste tipping feed contract contingent upon the submission of required documents
and approve city manager.
for his designated design notice to proceed.
Hi.
Hi, my birthday.
Awesome.
Thank you.
Before the disposal service, your BA tells you,
thanks so that we went out for Ben,
we had one responder.
In the past two that I've been involved in,
we had three and four, I believe,
respond to that.
It is a warning in the response,
but it's right in mind with the rest of mind.
A new bid solicitations this year,
because of fuel prices,
or not going to come in,
especially for a year.
This is a six month request for
to be the cost.
So first of all,
the very fact that we only had one response
is reason enough to go back out for Ben,
if you want to.
Actually looking for direction for you on this,
because you have a few options.
The price that they,
with those on their game,
which is our current contractor,
and to mine all,
we're not unhappy with our current contractor.
But it was twice the cost.
It's a six month bid at twice the cost,
which means that you're looking at spending
our entire one year,
budget,
for tipping fees,
and six month contract.
So for clarity,
this is what we're paying
some company to come to our facility,
and always containers off to you,
some way and fill somewhere.
We love the trailers,
we love the trailers.
Now, when we ask for their,
when they're fed,
we ask them to hold us both
for them to do the work,
or for us to supply
the name power and resources.
So,
how are we going to give you probably
a break down on how that is
or is it cost effective to do it ourselves?
Is there a reason why we don't go back
to do it ourselves?
That's kind of what we wanted to
test tonight,
but as far as the different ideas,
maybe we can create this month
and that's what we can obviously keep
crash moving in then.
I'm just going to give you an idea.
I mean,
we've got the equipment right.
We've got the truck.
But I mean,
we look at this bid.
I mean,
so just so everybody knows
that we're going to be able
to do this week.
There's 20,000 pounds of total.
So,
month by that time,
66 is a pretty big deal.
It's my understanding, too, that you might come up short on actual manpower.
Yes, we would have to.
That's what something we want to have time to know.
We just open these bids.
We obviously need to keep continuing on my trash service.
We want to look at all of the options.
Obviously, we can afford to pay 6623 in time.
So your options include going back up or been.
Of course, then we still have the concept of possible scenario of gas prices continuing to rise in six months.
I am not any type of projection, you're a person.
I've looked out there and you know, it depends on who you ask and what they're trying to sell you.
Whether or not gas prices are going to stabilize or get higher or taper off.
We can hire third party as tireless and justing to do work.
We can do it ourselves in house.
The members who I don't look favorable to do.
They what we would say been having a third party do it would be the extra.
Bences of the fees that WCA is adding on to their tipping fees.
Which is significant to them.
What here for you and if you want to take on this.
To another time.
That's how long do we got.
This is the story.
On this contract.
Contracts.
So.
And so now we have WCA.
And we have to think to use this as a fact on.
We have to think to use this as a fact on our tipping fees.
We think that they are mean.
We charge 50 $.
We take trash in and that's how it's through around.
We're struggling on that.
We don't take trash in to you.
Well, we can't raise up trash.
We're already raising like.
I think we probably need to think about maybe building a damn house.
And also this has an effect on sprinkling.
I mean, you know.
And I can't.
For these libraries.
I mean.
Cut it out.
I mean, if you think that we.
Thousands of years.
I mean, 21.
If you take 21,000.
10.
I mean, that's only $.
How long has it been since we've done it in half?
Eight years.
I mean.
I mean, here.
Well, it's.
City might really need to.
They need their own.
And that's what kind of piece of property to purchase.
And.
And we've got a small piece of property.
Uh.
We've got a small piece of property.
It's a train mail right in the center of peace.
I have no clue what that means in the world.
It's not much.
Well, the only way it feels was out.
How the old warm-out plan was it not?
Yes.
And then if we was to, I mean, look into that.
Awesome.
This is, I mean, we just think of the economy.
Thanks for doing that.
I mean, we're starting to hear nothing's building.
We start to know this human.
That's awesome.
It's going to be.
That's our key kind of contribution.
We start to believe that.
What's up?
Has anybody talked to the county about that?
Because of the land fields and stuff that I have over there.
I talked to this to this data about it.
And they said, we got data to them in their agreement.
And I just...
What does start across looks like for us to...
I mean, it's not just about buying a piece of property.
It's about...
You're going to have to have to have equipment to dig in.
Yeah.
I mean, it seems like significant cost to get started.
Obviously, when you've got started, you're...
You're good for a while.
But there's other cities in there.
I know.
We'll have a chance.
What do we have?
I don't know.
Can we do that?
Mm-hmm.
We use it.
I know that miners and...
I'm sure there's plenty of them open.
Not inexpensive anyway.
Sure.
But the Canada wants more than the new right.
Did you have until the end of the night?
I think probably the best thing to do is look at this from every different angle.
We need to come up with some of them.
We need to come up with some cost analysis and come up with...
You know, maybe four options of...
Do we just continue to do what we're doing?
Do we do it ourselves?
Do we do a land fill?
I mean, sure there's a fourth and maybe even a fifth option of what we do.
We just got to come up with some way that we don't continue to put burden on.
We'll be all there.
Start burning it again.
I used to do that by the way.
I was employed at the sanitation group.
I had one point.
That's what I'm going to require.
No, it wasn't.
Not I was working there when I happened.
I never did.
Why do we quit?
EPA mostly, right?
It wasn't up to date.
Okay.
And it was going to cost over million dollars per grain of a day.
And they didn't go to the...
Now it's going to be $1.00 in your business.
It's what I've been told.
I wasn't there yet.
Okay.
There was a lot of issues with the scrubbers and how the EPA was looking at those and the upgrades we were going to have to do.
But I worked here.
That's what I remember.
It all being about the scrubbers.
I remember hating having to go in on that fourth weekend of the month and clean it out of the duct work and it's hot.
Can we put this on hold to for a month and pay?
Well technically that's really what they're here asking is we want to just put this see there on the six-month or month a month
so that Tyler can finish his
fiscal research and bring back options with some financial components to it that's really going to give you the cost element of each one
We've he's been
exhaustively reaching out and in
kicking over every rock you can find but
He's waiting on a lot of people to call him back and he really wants to get all those numbers together before we present anything
How many acres does it take to create a 34 year
possibility
complainers are many
I say how
So you're recommended 60
One saying to save some of the budget that maybe we need to not have three Saturdays until we come up with the resolution
Of what needs to happen
So I mean, there's a look at them. There's a lot that comes in on those three Saturdays. I know sitting at the soccer field. Saturday morning
Let me answer two I can track it. Well when we open a starting morning there was seven
setting the way for us to open. That was already there
Then keeping in mind that that would be even if we did it on a temporary basis
We during these economic times right now of instability
That's something we need to seriously consider because that is an extensive cost that we have and as much as it adds value to the community of providing this way to get
additional junk garbage out of our community
During these economic times it's difficult for us to even know what that cost is gonna be
This entire calendar
Previous years when we've done that we do what our budget was we knew what our contracts were right now
We're in a little bit of unknown so as we continue to take in
junk garbage when these
Pre days we really don't know the full impact to that
It's not a bad idea to consider
Putting a pin in that for a while until we see where the economy is going
The first five months of this year
It would have cost us 15,000 or four it has cost us 15,000 just for free side of it
And our new different season. We've been twice that more than four than twice that, right?
Me and the grand scheme of things that ain't a lot
So it's worth to people that are coming in there and paying about the time right now have you changed?
That price yet?
Yeah.
That's what we're trying to really create a way to get a low goal is to find a solution that
would fit within the current rate structure.
So you're just going to have back there and so they don't fit.
That's fine.
We've got a football field behind my house on the north coast, we can big it up, but I can
go ahead and fill that with it.
Just temporary.
I'm sure they'll like that.
And being calling it, calling it being as way, we'll protect the people.
You have to agree with that.
So when you're getting action to table this time, for six to two, now you need to approve
it on, not to waste this.
Otherwise, they're stuck with all of the tracks.
So the current contract has expired and so they're wanting to renew a contract with
this existing contract that we've had, but only on a month and a month while we, for one,
go out and figure out if we can get people a bit that would bid, that's what we got one.
It's going to try to find more bidders and then look at the cost of the other options that we have.
And we're improving that for up to 60 days, but it would be a different kind of study.
There's your one in Riverton, going there, you know, that's what I thought, that's what I thought, that's what I thought.
And the one in Columbus, and north of Columbus, I'll make a motion that we put it on the 30 day,
no, come up.
It's like a day.
So go.
Hi.
All right.
December.
Hi.
Thank you.
New business, which is the residents in the post, you know, this agenda, and they could have
not have been anticipated prior to the time of posting, trustee community announcements.
adjournment.
So move.
Thank you.
Please sit.